A. Marlena Keller

Saint Paul, MN | Email | GitHub | LinkedIn

Summary

Entry-level React developer with leadership experience and technical know-how. Previous experience includes analyzing and troubleshooting technical issues. Has worked collaboratively on projects to build full stack applications. Strengths include learning new technologies on the fly and project collaboration. Strong interpersonal and communication skills make me an invaluable team member. Recently earned a certificate through the University of Minnesota Full Stack Coding Bootcamp - equivalent to a 12-week internship. Enjoy cross-functional team efforts, taking on new challenges, and using technical skills to make positive impacts.

Education

University of Minnesota - Minneapolis, MN

Full Stack Developer Coding Bootcamp Certificate

June 2023

Saint Paul College - Saint Paul, MN

Associate's in Applied Science, Computer Programming

May 2017

Skills

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, React.js, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Bootstrap, Bulma, Express.js, Progressive Web Applications, Responsive Design, Local Storage, Session Storage, User Authentication, MERN Stack, Model-View-Controller, Application Programming Interface, Rest, JSON, AJAX, HTTP Request Methods, GraphQL, Agile, Heroku, Git, GitHub, Continuous Integration, Scripts. Some past experience with Python and Java.

Professional Experience

Operations Analyst

July 2017 - March 2023

State of Minnesota - Saint Paul, MN

- Analyzed tech queue escalation tickets to troubleshoot technical issues with the MNsure website
- Experience with administrative, organizational, and analysis skills, including time and priority management, sufficient to work on several projects simultaneously in a fast paced environment within deadlines
- Knowledge of state and federal regulations governing Minnesota Assistance Programs, including: processes, procedures, appeals, regulations, and determining eligibility

Reimbursement Analyst

October 2014 - August 2016

Boston Scientific - Arden Hills, MN

- Analyzed large-volume legal contracts to determine eligibility for reimbursement
- Processed large-scale payments through SAP and CRM
- Identified need for standardized procedures, streamlined processes
- Developed new training materials for incoming analysts
- Ability to work independently and accurately, problem-solve, and meet deadlines

Volunteer Experience

Founder November 2022 - Present

Mediocre Outdoorsy - Saint Paul, MN

- Founder of a 500+ member women's walking and hiking group for individuals who want to be active and meet others, but don't consider themselves highly athletic
- Organize and host twice-monthly events and manage a team of six volunteers who lead events with me as well as on the organization's behalf